victorpresumido

Senior Data Engineer

about

30 years old Porto

contact

victor.presumido@gmail.com github.com/victorpre

languages

portuguese native english fluent german basic

programming

Ruby on Rails (strong)
Elixir Phoenix (strong)
Scala (strong)
Java (medium)

skills

MySQL/PostgreSQL Redis Kafka RabbitMQ Git Hadoop/Hive SCRUM/Kanban TDD

interests

software development, mechanical keyboards, coffee

education

Federal University of São Paulo

São José dos Campos, Brazil

B.S. in Computer Science

Pace University New York, USA

B.S. in Computer Science

BSMP scholarship sponsored by the Brazilian government.

experience

NEW WORK SE - (Senior) Data Engineer

may 2021 - present

fall 2015 - spring 2016

GPA: 3.85/4.00

2013 - 2016

Porto, Portugal

After some years in the company working primarily with Ruby and living/working in Hamburg, Germany I decided to embrace some change and since 2021 I switched roles and started working as a Data Engineer focused on Scala and in mid 2022 I relocated to Porto. I'm embedded in the Marketing Solutions Data Science team.

NEW WORK SE - (Senior) Software Engineer

may 2018 - may 2021

Hamburg, Germany

Worked as a Backend developer using mainly Ruby On Rails, MySQL, RabbitMQ.

Gympass - Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer São Paulo, Brazil

feb. 2017 - apr. 2018

Maintenance and improvement of the web application, including adding features such as a self checkin service adaptive Help Center for internal and external customers. Main technologies: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JavaScript, MySQL, Git.

Quero Educação - Ruby on Rails Full Stack Developer São José dos Campos, Brazil

jul. 2014 - jul. 2015

Maintenance of system. Development and integration of third-part metrics solutions (Mixpanel, Kissmetrics).

Fiducia IT AG - Java Developer (Praktikum)

may 2013 - nov. 2013

Karlsruhe, Germany

Part of a multicultural team formed by 5 people from different parts of the world. Responsible for developing a prototype of an innovative solution of integrating banking software with social media.

MARS Inc - Storage & Backup Intern

feb. 2012 - apr. 2013

Guararema, Brazil

Responsible for monitoring databases health and metrics analysis. Developed a project of proactive backup monitoring. 3PAR disks provisioning.

VICTOR PRESUMIDO